Guide to the United Ministries in Higher Education Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Addendum: Verlyn Barker Files, Series IX
  Full listings of papers and books donated by Verlyn Baker in 2006 are in Box 61, Folder 1. See Series IV, Publications, for related papers and articles.
  - Conference proceedings
    - Larry T. McGehee and Mary Beth Taylor. "The Work of the University in the United States." Proceedings of a Conference for the National Council of the United Campus Christian Fellowship. August 29-September 3, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - United Ministries in Higher Education, Southern California: Daniel G. Aldrich, Jr. "Higher Education, The Church and Campus Ministry" October 15, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - West Coast Consultation on Higher Education Participants. Mercy Center, Burlingame, CA. March 1-3, 1992, including papers by Clyde O. Robinson, Jr. and Davida Foy Crabtree (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - The Church and Higher Education Regional Consultation, St. Malo Retreat and Conference Center, Colorado, Ocotber 22-24, 1995, including papers by Verlyn L. Barker, Donald Messer, Maureen Curnow, and others (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - United Ministries in Higher Education papers
    - Two papers by E. I. Abenroth, including "The Church's Ministry in Higher Education: Selected Statements from Documents and Individuals", 1976 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Eight papers by Verlyn L. Barker, including "Historical Perspective on Ministry in Higher Education", "The Minister in Higher Education: Theologian, Mentor, and Educator", 1982-1993 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Papers by William Birenbaum, Neil W. Brown, John Butler, L. Wayne Bryan, John E. Cantelon, John J. Carey, Malcolm H. Davis, 1958-1992 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Papers by John Duley, Russell R. Dynes, David E. Engel and Earl J. Lowell, Cecil Findley, William Hallman, 1967-1970s (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Papers by Edward M. Huenemann, H. Lynn Jondahl, Bert Keller, Clifton W. Kerr, Tom Lasswell, Marna J. McKenzie, 1969-1984 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Papers by James B. Miller, Hugh Nevin, David C. Rich, Clyde O. Robinson, Jr., Gayle L. Sandholm, 1963-1990 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Papers by Leo Sandon, Jr., William Shinto, Verne Sindlinger, Gerald H. Slusser, Daven Steffenson, Jessica P. Stickney, Darrell Yeaney, 1971-1996 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Other articles and essays
    - Papers by David A. Ames, Beverly A. Asbury, Dorothy C. Bass, 1981-1992 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Papers by John N. Brittain, Allan J. Burry, Frank Alsid de Chambeau, Robert W. Clarke, John R. Cobb, Jr., 1967-1996 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Papers by Robert Conn, Laurent A. Parks Daloz, Walther R. Dettweiler, J. Edward Dirks, Richard L. Elliott, Robert Epps, 1961-1996 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Papers by Eugene E. Erickson, Andrew Foster, Mark Harris, Paul Harrison, Stanley Hauerwas, John E. Hines, Joseph C. Hough, Jr., James A. Joseph, 1964-1985 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Papers by James T. Laney, Bruce Larson, James A. Martin, Jr., Archibald MacLeish, Robert Michaelson, 1959-2000 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Papers by Ralph L. Moellering, Frederick Niedner, Hugh C. Noble, Wayne E. Olson, Albert C. Outler, Sharon Daloz Parks, Jaroslav Pelikan, 1954-2001 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Papers by Philip H. Phenix, William Rankin, Parker Rossman, Richard L. Rubenstein, Donna Schaper, Harold K. Schilling, 1959-2001 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Papers by Donald G. Shockley, Douglas Sloan, Krister Stendahl, Phil Stephan, Allison Stokes, Richard Tappan, John F. A. Taylor, Glenn Tinder, 1964-1997 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Papers by Thomas Trotter, Bob Turner, Kenneth Underwood, John E. Walsh, Malcolm L. Warford, George H. Williams, World Student Christian Federation, Tadanor Yamashita, Philip T. Zabriskie, 1958-2002 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets
    - "The Role of the University Chaplain" by John E. Cantelon, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - "The Task of the Christian in the University" by A. J. Coleman, 1947 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - "The Protestant Stake in Higher Education" by Merrimon Cuninggim, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - "The University and the Church" and "The Role of the Church in Higher Education" by Harold K. Schilling, 1955, 1958 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - "Christian Obedience in the University" - Student Christian Movement in Britain, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - "The Christian Scholar" by Cornelius Van Til, 1959 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - "The Theological Idea of the University" by George H. Williams, 1958 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - "The Christian Community in the Academic World" - statement of the World Student Christian Federation, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Journal issues: Student World: "Christians in the University"; Cross Currents: "The Once and Future University", 1965, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation
    - Boston University doctoral dissertation of Darrell Yeaney: "The United Ministries in Higher Education: A Historical and Critical Appraisal", 1975 (Box 63, Folder 1)